Hello hi friends welcome to our channel
friends we all should take front health insurance
because it protects you and
your family from any
planned or unplanned medical expenses
this especially in today's time where
medical bills and
hospitalization bills can be very high during the corona period
and friends many
companies are offering health insurance in the market and to make
this decision easier which
company's product should you use we are going to
compare in this video some of the
top health insurance companies of India in
which we have included Star Health
Insurance Care Health Insurance Max
Bupa whose name has been changed to Nibha
so we are going to see the details of all these companies
and in the end we will compare the
premium so do watch the video till the end
friends in this I would like to tell you that
we have shortlisted these companies because
not only these are top health insurance companies
but this company
provides only health care so from the side it will be a
very good focus
for these companies in claim registration
friends before we move on I
would like to tell you that I do not have any urgent need
from any company  The
purpose of making this video is so that you
can take the best decision for yourself. Friends, please subscribe to our channel in Pant Saathi
and
take the time you see on the screen so that you get my latest videos
first. Before going into the details of the print policy, first of all let's
look at the statistics of these
three companies. If we
click on the trees of IRDA, which is
India's health related regulatory body
and the last one was published in December 21,
this statistics tells us
how much the company has returned out of the total premium collected from all the customers.
In clean, for any good health insurance company,
this should be between 52.90 percent.
If we talk about Star Health
Insurance, then this statistics is 94.4.
Next, if we talk about Max Bupa or Nimbu, then
this is 56.09. For Sure Health
Insurance, this statistics is 55.15 percent. So
friends, you can see here
these statistics for Star Health Insurance
and even more than healthy
In this video we have compared the
top order systems of these three health insurance companies.
We have
chosen Star Comprehensive Plan in Max Bupa,
Health Camp Yauvan and Care Health
Insurance.
Friends, let's move ahead and compare them. The
first and important
parameter is Sum Insured. This shows
how much maximum reimbursement you will get at the time of insurance.
If we
talk about Star Comprehensive, then here you
can choose a minimum policy of Rs 5 lakh
and a maximum of Rs 1 crore. If we talk about Mahesh Bhatt or
Lemon, then you
can choose a policy of up to Rs 1 crore for free
and if we look at Care, here you
can choose a policy of up to Rs 275 lakh for free.
Friends, all these plans
are available on individual and family basis. If you
use Pearl Water Plan, then the amount that is there is the
total amount for the entire family.
And here if I talk about Care, then it is Rs
93 lakh.
Even the members of your family are in the first line, but
friends, I would not suggest this
because your sum insured gets
divided among so many people and it is possible that at the
time of need, they may
not be available. In short, at the time of need, friends, let's talk about
hospitalization expenses. If you get
hospitalized and it is for
more than an hour, then all your medical
expenses are covered in this, which includes accurate
doctor's pay, room rent,
anesthesia, cost of blood medicine,
diagnostic 410 etc. Friends, all these are
covered in all three policies and
single private AC room
is included in all three policies, but if you were in care or if you are
taking a policy, then there is
some typing on room rent and your
room rent cannot be more than one per cent of minutes per day.
Similarly, there
is camping in ICU also. If you are taking a policy of three and four
and you
cannot subscribe to free
hospitalization, that is, if you get hospitalized, then even
before that,
your concentration
medicine will be covered.  There are charts here,
if we subscribe, the
30-day subscription cover is provided and
post-hospitalization cover is also provided in the same manner.
If we talk about the No Claim Bonus, we
can see the coverage and care in the Sixteenth Insurance. Here,
Star is much better compared to other policies. Let's compare the
No Claim Bonus.
Suppose you have taken a policy and have
not made any claim in the entire policy and you will renew it next year, then
a bonus will automatically be added to your sum insured
without any additional premium. If we
talk about Star Comprehensive, then if
you do not make any claim in the first year, then
your sum insured will automatically increase by 50% in the
next year and if you do not make any claim in the next year also, then
your sum insured will
double after 2 years. But if you
take a policy above Rs 1.5 lakh, then
your sum insured will double only after the first clean free cover.
Talking about Municipal Corporation, here
your claim premium will
increase by 20% in every claim and it will
double up to a maximum of 100%.  It is possible that in the same way,
if we talk about the policy, then here the maximum premium will be charged every
year and it
can increase to a maximum of 50% or more,
but some additional advance
is also available here, which is named as NCB Super
Premium. If you
take this policy, then your premium will increase
every year and apart from that, it will
increase by another 50% and this increase can reach a maximum of
50%. The thing to be seen here is that
whenever you fly any
airplane, your bonus will
fall at the same rate at which it increases, but
here it can never be less than the basic sum insured at the gate.
But friends,
if we talk about the disadvantages of the policy, then the
advantage of this policy is that whenever you make a
claim on the house, the amount of
premium and your already increased amount will
never decrease. Let us understand this with an example.
Suppose Ram
took a Pan Life policy for himself and he did
not make a quick claim in the first year, then
in the stock comparison, this  It will increase by hundred percent, that is,
his basic salary will start at
20 lakhs and if he has taken on lemon, then it will
increase by 20% here, that is, it will increase to twelve lakhs
and if he has
chosen NCB care premium, then here it will
increase by 50% plus time per send, that is,
from six lakhs and it will increase to
sixteen lakhs and in the same way, if
he does not make any claim in the second year also, then in
Star, because the hundred
percent maximum has already been increased, it will increase only till T20 Live
and if it does not happen, if we talk about opposition, then
here this photo will increase by 20% more
and if we
talk about care as well as super premium, then here it will
increase by six percent more and it will reach twenty-two lakhs,
friends, suppose now Ram
cleans in the third year, then
in Star Comprehensive, it will fall by 50% and will
come back shooting because the lemon vitamin which
increases, it will not fall, otherwise it will remain the same, but if it does
not increase further, then it will remain
fertilizer, if we talk about care here, then
this  It will fall from 60% and will be back
to sixteen percent. Friends, so let's
move ahead to our next feature,
Restoration Benefit. Whenever you make
any claim in the policy and your sum
insured and no claim bonus gets
combined, then the company automatically
reviews and re-adds the basic benefit to your policy for the
next claim.
If we talk about Star Comprehensive,
then this feature is available and the best thing is
that here you can also avail the benefit again.
If we talk about
Resident Remedy Help Companies and Care Health
Insurance, then this feature
is available here also, but you cannot avail the benefit in both the Explanation.
Friends, let's talk about treatment
where your hospitalization is less than 28 years,
then all three policies are
covered in it, but the thing to be noted here is
that you cannot avail the benefit in your To PDF and Depression
department.
Friends, let's talk about other
treatment or hospitalization,
but the patient's condition is such that he has to be
shifted from the hospital.  If it cannot be done or the patient
is not available, then he can take treatment from a
medical practitioner under his supervision,
but here the
hospitalization should be for more than three days at home.
Friends, if we talk about
this facility is available in all the three policies,
but the maximum limit for care is up to
ten percent of the sum insured.
Friends, let's talk about ambulance.
If there is hospitalization, then all the
three policies offer you the ambulance feature.
If we talk about Star
Comprehensive, then there will be actress
award on this. If we
talk about Max Bupa or oil companies, then there will be
hospitalization on shades. If we
talk about clear, then it depends on
your policy review board. For Indian Flag
policy, it is hospitalization on 100.
In a policy of 50 lakhs, it
is the 12th hospitalization and in 5250 Cardamom
policy, it is hospitalization on 2.50 and
in policies above that, it is
hospitalization on 3 thousand. Let's talk about
organ donor expenses.  This
is covered in all three policies and here the limit is up
to your sum insured but if we talk about it then
here in three and four like
policies the limit is up to phase, in 510 like
policy this limit is up to tubelight in one like
policy of 5240 lakhs this limit is up to
tubelight and in 5275 lakhs policy
this limit is up to free life and
snacks let's talk about maternity cover i.e.
expenses incurred in child birth which is
not comprehensive but it is available here
from some limit if we talk about 5 lakhs
policy then here normal
delivery cover is
1000 to 1.5 lakhs policy
from Chanakya Limited 2518 to Zor Actively if we
look at the policy of train like it well up to 5 lakhs then
this limit is 34540 respectfully if it is
more than free life if we talk about one crore policy then
this limit is phase and one like
respectfully but friends here in care
and help companies this  The facility is
not available at all. Friends,
I would like to tell you here that the
minimum waiting period for using this facility in Star Comprehensive
is two years. Friends, let's
talk about OPD, i.e. Heart Patient
Department. This facility
is available in Star Health. If
you take a continuation policy for three years, then
after that you get a limit of Rs. 5,000.
Friends, if you
consult in OPD, then you get up
to Rs. 21, where the consultation is
Rs. 304. No
such feature is available in Health Companies and Care.
Friends, if we talk about AYUSH or
alternative treatment, then
it is available in all three policies, but here there are
some sub-limits in Star Comprehensive and Care,
it depends on the
policy amount. There is
no limit on the treatment of Help Companies.
Friends, if we talk about health checkup, then all
three policies offer the option of One Saiyaan Health Checkup.
But here in Star Comparability it
is available only in plain fear.
Before taking any policy, it is important to
understand its exclusions. If we
talk about waiting period, then if we
take this policy, then for any medical claim
you will have to wait for 30 days except accident
and if we talk about
pre-existing disease, then here in
Star Comparability the waiting period
is three years. In health companies the waiting period is
of 3S and in Care the
waiting period is of four years. Friends, as per the
guidelines of one and a half years, the
waiting period for some specific diseases is
two years, which includes categories like
joint replacement, hernia
etc. Apart from this, there are many diseases
like congenital disease i.e.
birth control, sexually
transmitted disease like HIV etc.
These are also not covered in all three policies.
Friends, apart from this, any drug or
alcohol is not covered by you.  All the three
policies do not settle any claim on the decision made,
friend, let us now move ahead and
compare the premium of all the three policies.
Suppose Ram, whose age is thirty years,
takes a policy of Rs 10 lakh for himself and his sister, whose age is eight years, Ram does
not have any habit of smoking or consuming two back to back, so let us
see his premium. If he takes Star Low
Pressure, then his annual premium is
Rs 8 to 1000. If he takes Health Care,
then his premium is Rs 30.
If he takes Care's NCB Super Premium, then
his annual premium is
Rs 3008. So here you can see that the
premium of other health companies is almost
equal, but you have to pay a little more premium in Star Health.
But
here I would like to tell that as we
saw, you also get some additional features in Star, in which
you get restoration cover, and
for Nilesh also,
here you also get some OPD advantages.
Along with this, I would like to tell you  You
also get the benefit of maternity, so friends, you can choose
your best plan according to your requirement and convenience.
Friends, in the end,
I would like to tell you that you
can also compare these plans yourself. For that, you
can go to the Policy Bazaar app or this site
and compare it yourself by following these lines.
I have also put its link in the description below,
you can go there too.
Friends, I hope you liked this video.
If you have any questions related to airplane,
then definitely put them in the comment section.
And before leaving, I would request you to
definitely subscribe to our channel and also
like and share this video and press the bell that is
visible on your screen.
Thank you and stay healthy.